NYSUT Boards of Directors Meetings. 6174/015
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Resolution Committee, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  List of committee members
- Interview Team for Retirement Board Candidates, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  Minutes of NYSUT Retirement Delegate Candidate Interview committee, July 1, 1973; excerpt of Executive Committee minutes appointing committee
- Special Assistance Committee, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  Financial statement for Mary Muldoon (Welfare) Fund, August 9, 1974; list of trustees and roll call vote; resolution that Muldoon Fund Committee be made a standing committee
- Teacher Education and Certification Committee, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  Recommendations to NYSUT vice president Toni Cortese for Executive Committee position re performance-based teacher certification, November 29, 1973; list of committee members
- Committee to Make Recommendations on Aid to Striking Locals, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  List of members of Committee on Striking Locals; committee's unanimous recommendations
- Welfare Trust Committee, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Committee to Study the Goals for Elem. Sec. and Continuing Education, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  State Education Department discussion paper (revised), Goals for Elementary, Secondary and Continuing Education in New York State, November 1973; preliminary reports of committee; list of committee members
- NEA Constitutional Transition Committee, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Convention Tellers and Sergeants-at-Arms, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  List of members
- Committee to Rec. Endorsement for Retirement Board Member, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  Text of resolution by NYSUT Board of Directors endorsing member for New York State Teachers Retirement Board; newspaper clipping re establishment of committee to consider candidates for teacher position on state retirement board
- Task Force on Retired Teachers, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  Resolution establishing task force; list of members
- Official Committee Appointments, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  Lists of committees and members
- Class Size Committee, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  List of committee members; resolution establishing committee; mid- year report; interim report; final report, February 1976
- Civil and Human Rights Committee, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Educational Issues Committee, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  List of committee members; proposed NYSUT position statement on physical education; proposed position statement on mainstreaming
- Educational Program Transfers Committee, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  List of committee members; resolution establishing committee
- Human Relations Coordinating Council Reps, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 54)
- Legal Review Committee, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 55)
- NYSEE/NYSUT Liaison, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  Name and contact information for liaison
- Pension/Retirement Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  List of committee members; resolution establishing committee; report on activities and recommendations; Executive Committee minutes re actions on recommendations, January 2, 1975
- Political Action Committee-VOTE/COPE Mgmt, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  List of committee members; resolutions; VOTE/COPE poster; instruction sheet for local presidents and chapter chairmen
- Redistricting Ad Hoc Committee, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  List of committee members; resolution establishing committee; recommendation of committee
- Committee to Review Retirement Conv. Procedures, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  List of committee members; resolution creating committee
- Special Assistance Committee (Muldoon Fund), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  List of committee members; financial statements
- Special Education Committee, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 62)
- Teacher Education and Certification Committee, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  List of committee members; newspaper clipping from New York Teacher re NYSUT president Tom Hobart's opinion on commissioner's task force recommendations
- Welfare Trust Committee, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  List of committee members; excerpt of welfare fund bylaws re trustees
- Defense Fund Committee, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  List of committee members; resolutions creating committee to study defense fund for strikes
- Panel for Dispute Settlement, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  Notation that structure was yet to be defined in relation to Landrum-Griffin Act
- Committee to Advise on Trade and Industrial Teacher Concerns, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  Clipping from New York Teachers re committee to advise on trade (vocational education)
- Board Committee, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  Resolution creating committee to study procedure for submitting director resolutions
- Bicentennial Committee, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  List of members; report
- Board of Directors, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  Directory, 1974-75 and 1975-76; District Director Election Guidelines (to fill a vacancy) as amended at September 26-27, 1975, board meeting; memo to NYSUT president Tom Hobart re cost comparison for board meeting sites, April 16, 1975; ballot for election district director; roll call vote record for election of Executive Committee members; letter from NYSUT president Tom Hobart to Board of Directors re dispute with NEA president James Harris over procedure for meeting, April 11, 1975
- NYSUT Committee Files, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  Form letters for committee nominees; list of members, final report, New York Times article, and correspondence re Committee to Study Class Size, including letter of resignation
- Catherine R. Lloyd, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  Lists of committee members; NYSUT Board of Directors directories, 1974-75 and 1975-76; reports of Committee on Committees and Committee Appointments
- Sergeant-at-Arms, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  Lists of sergeants-at-arms; description of responsibilities; blank volunteer forms
- Credentials Committee, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  List of Credentials Committee members; proposed procedure for registering representatives; procedure for roll call votes; roll call summary report form
- Convention Committee, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  List of Convention Committee members
- Elections Committee, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 76)
- Resolutions Committee Chairmen, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  List of chairpersons
- Ad Hoc Committee Effect of Hurd Decision on Cities, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  Newspaper clippings; list of members of Ad Hoc Committee on Problems of the Small Cities and invitation from NYSUT director of legislation to dinner meeting with state legislators re Hurd decision and corrective legislation
- Task Force on Affirmative Action, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 79)
- Tellers, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  List for Representative Assembly; description of tellers' responsibilities
- Committee of Executive Committee to Study Salary and Fringe Benefits for NYSUT Officers, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  Description of committee charge and list of members; minutes of Board of Directors and Executive Committee meetings re committee; memo to Board of Directors from committee chair
- Credentials Committee, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  Lists of members for 1974 and 1975 Representative Assembly and associated Election Districts; letter to member of committee; proposed procedure for registration
- Elections Committee, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 83)
- Resolutions Committee Chairmen, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  Lists of committees and chairs
- Sergeants-at-Arms, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  Lists of names and addresses
- Tellers, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 86)
- Ad Hoc Committee License Standards for Vocational Shop Teachers, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  List of members of Ad Hoc Committee on State Certification Requirements for Teachers of Shop Subjects
- Convention Committee, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  List of members; headquarters registration form
- Committee Cumulative File, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  Board of Directors Directories, 1976-77 and 1977-78; lists of members of various committees
- Committee Posted, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  Board of Directors Directory, 1973-74; NYSUT Constitution; list of members of NEA Constitutional Transition Committee
- Committees-NYSUT Services, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  Memo re auditor's report; report by NYSUT Committee on Services; list of members of Committee on Services to Locals; questionnaire for locals re NYSUT services; correspondence re Committee to Study NYSUT Services; list of NYSUT services; committee meeting notices; final report of NYSUT Committee on Membership Services, October 20, 1979; Division of Field Services Special Report for Committee on NYSUT Services, March 30, 1979
- Committees-Professional Development Task Force, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  Memo re budgetary implications of resolutions adopted by Representative Assembly, May 4, 1978; resolution calling for establishment of division for professional development
- Committees-Redistricting, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  List of committee members; committee recommendations; meeting notices; analyses of active per capita entitlements for NYSUT election districts (geographical and non-geographical) as of 1978 Representative Assembly; Representative Assembly entitlement report as of February 28, 1978
- Committees-Resolutions, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  List of recommended resolutions committee chairmen; Report of the Board Sub-Committee to Study Referred Resolutions (memo to Board of Directors); letter (with photo) to NYSUT president Tom Hobart from Emma (Deeble?), chair of Committee on Civil and Human Rights, April 9, 1979; letters from others accepting chairmanships; letters from Hobart informing members of chair nominations
- Committees-Retired Teachers Task Force, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  List of task force members, 1980-82; lists, n.d.; memo to Executive Committee discussing results of survey of NYSUT retirees, February 14, 1980
- Committees-Dorothy Silverman (Committee to Elect), 1978 (Box 4, Folder 96)
  Lists of members of Committee to Elect Dorothy Silverman; letter to retirement delegates re need to replace teacher-member of New York State Teachers' Retirement System Board, urging election of Dorothy Silverman
- Committees-Central Labor Councils Task Force, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 97)
  Excerpt from Board of Directors summary minutes appointing members to Task Force on Local Labor Councils; list of recommended members
- Committees-Credit Union (Feasibility of Statewide), 1978 (Box 4, Folder 98)
  NYSUT credit union survey; corrected Board of Directors minutes noting establishment of Committee to Study the Feasibility of a Statewide Credit Union
- Committees-Educational Issues, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 99)
  List of members; letters of resignation; policy on writing skills; proposed policy for the teaching of composition; letters to nominated members; correspondence
- Committee on Excessing, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 100)
  Meeting notice and agenda; report of the committee, March 1981; list of members; correspondence with coordinator of workshops for excessed teachers
- James E. Allen Award, 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 101)
  Administrative and Executive Committee minutes with resolutions on whether to award the James E. Allen, Jr., Award that year, 1973-74; State Education Department press release, "George W. Angell Receives Allen Memorial Award," April 21, 1978; newspaper clipping, "Guidelines Set for James E. Allen Award," June 16, 1972; memorial notice re former Education Commissioner James E. Allen and citation for Alfred E. Smith Award, 1971
- Committees-Financial Review, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 102)
  Committee recommendations; meeting notice and agenda; letter to NYSUT president Tom Hobart from committee chair, suggesting he replace her because of ill health, December 28, 1978
- Committees-Mainstreaming Task Force, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  List of committee members; meeting notice and agenda; minutes; State Education Department Report on Special Education Classification and Standards Project; State Education Department Report on State Aid for Programs for Pupils with Handicapping Conditions; State Education Department review guide for special education programs; State Education Department publication, "Services for the Handicapped: Linking Special Education, Occupational Education, and Vocational Rehabilitation," October 1979; minutes of Special Education Committee meeting with Louis Grumet (Deputy Commissioner), January 26, 1980; background paper, Teaching Children with Handicapping Conditions; NYSUT Policy Statement on Mainstreaming; Learning Characteristics of the Retarded vs Normal; correspondence
- Dean Streiff Chronological Files, 1973-1981 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  Outgoing correspondence from Dean Streiff, assistant to the president of NYSUT
- Arvid Burke Fellowship, 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  New York State Teachers Association press release announcing first winner of the Arvid J. Burke Fellowship in Educational Administration, August 22 (1967?); press release announcing establishment of the fellowship, May 7, 1967; press release announcing 1968 winner; letter from NYSTA president Emanuel Kafka to fellowship winner William White, June 23, 1970; newspaper clippings
- Arvie Eldred Citation, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Call for nominations; nomination forms; irate letter from local re failure to select winner, and reply from NYSTA executive secretary G. Howard Goold, December 4, 1952; list of selection committee members; correspondence with medal manufacturer; Proposed Statement on the Arvie Eldred Citation, announcing its replacement with the Arvie Eldred Scholarships
- Arvie Eldred Scholarships, 1953-1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  General information and nomination forms; NYSTA press release announcing 1970 winners; related newspaper clipping from NYSTA News Trends; 1969 press release and related clipping; announcements for 1957-67; summary of activities of scholarships winners, 1962; Report of the Arvie Eldred Scholarship Committee concerning suggested changes in the requirements for the scholarships, January 27, 1956; Revised Proposed Changes in General Information concerning the Arvie Eldred Scholarships, 1955; 1954 report on Arvie Eldred Scholarships; report, 1953; resolution abolishing the Arvie Eldred Scholarship, August 21, 1970
- G. Howard Goold Internship, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Application forms; correspondence; newspaper clippings re recipients; resolutions
- Alfred E. Smith Award Criteria, 1945-1967 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Award criteria and list of recipients; correspondence
- Alfred E. Smith Award, 1944-1961 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Nomination form for Alfred E. Smith Layman's Award for Conspicuous Service in Behalf of Public Education; list of award recipients as of 1956; citation for first award recipient, Edward Eastman, 1945; letter nominating Eastman from superintendent of Ithaca public schools; descriptions of subsequent award recipients; correspondence re rationale for establishing award, 1944; correspondence between award committee members; resolution that no award be made for 1961
- NYSTA-Alfred E. Smith Awards, 1962-1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Lists of award recipients, 1945-1973; Report to the Board of Directors from the Alfred E. Smith Award Committee, approved September 24, 1960; committee procedures and functions, 1960; award criteria; nomination form; citations for recipients
- Recruitment Committee for Executive Secy., 1971 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Minutes of special Board of Directors meeting to hear final report of Committee on Recruitment for an Executive Secretary, July 21, 1972; resolution appointing Vito DeLeonardis as Executive Secretary, October 14, 1972; recruitment materials; resolution in executive session appointing a search committee, March 17, 1972; print ad, omitting job description; interim report, noting many applicants had misread ad as secretarial position
- Dr. Francis J. White, Jr., 1969-1972 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Letter from NYSTA president Tom Hobart advising local presidents and delegates of resignation of Francis J. White, Jr., from position as Executive Secretary, because of change in authority, March 20, 1972; joint statement to Board of Directors by Hobart and White, March 17; statement of resignation by White, March 22; text of White's remarks at Board of Directors meeting, noting significant policy differences between himself and Hobart and other elected officers, March 17; Annual Report of the Executive Secretary, Dr. Francis J. White, Jr., to the House of Delegates of the New York State Teachers Association, November 7, 1971; announcement of appointment of White as Executive Secretary, August 1970; announcement for position of Executive Secretary, with clipping noting retirement of G. Howard Goold on July 1, 1970; Comprehensive Report and Recommendations to the Board of Directors from the Recruitment Committee, March 14, 1970; list of applicants; resumes
- Higher Education Institutions, 1968-1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  List of higher education institutions in New York State preparing teachers; list by State Education Department of colleges offering teacher education and certification programs, September 1974
- NYS and NYC Retirement Boards, 1973-1978 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Letter from NYSUT president Tom Hobart to local presidents, urging election of endorsed challenger candidate for teacher member of the New York State Teachers Retirement Board, June 7, 1978; letters from Hobart urging reelection of members, March 21, 1977, and November 18, 1975; newspaper clippings
- Charter Affiliates, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  NYSTA brochures re charter affiliation program; certificate; resolution establishing charter affiliation program, August 22, 1970; lists of charter affiliates
- Personnel Lists, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  NYSUT staff holiday mailing lists; description of job duties of officers; NYSUT telephone directory; NYSTA personnel list
- Dr. Francis J. White Correspondence, 1968-1971 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Report of Print Communications for New York State Teachers Association by Dr. George A Sanborn and Associates, Inc., June 15, 1968; memo to NYSTA executive secretary White re rationale for publications program, July 29, 1971; memo from White re air feasibility study, September 16, 1970; memo from White to Board of Directors re guidelines for service to members; first draft of proposal by White to Board of Directors, "A Proposal Relating to the Establishment of a Special Services Division for the New York State Teachers Association," December 1, 1970
- Uniserv Program and Organizing Allied Non Teaching Groups, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Reports by White to NYSTA Board of Directors, "Recommended Guidelines for Organizing Allied Non-Teaching Groups" and "A Proposal for a Unified Staff Service Program (UNISERV)," May 1971
- Student Education Association of NYS, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  Handbook for SEANYS (Student Education Association) Delegates to the New York State Teachers Association
- NYSTA is Your Voice (Box 5, Folder 17)
  Print brochure, c. 1965